Joyce Carol Oates Papers
Joyce Carol Oates Papers
- Memorabilia
  - Printed Material
    - Reviews (by title)
      - Anonymous Sins and Other Poems (Box 88)
      - The Assassins: A Book of Hours (Box 88)
      - The Assignation (Box 88)
      - "Bad Girls", Contemporary American Theatre Festival, Shepherdstown, WV; Georgia Repertory Theatre (Box 88)
      - Because It Is Bitter, and Because It Is My Heart, 2 folders (Box 88)
      - Bellefleur, 3 folders (Box 88)
      - The Best American Essays, 1991 (Box 88)
      - The Best American Short Stories, various years (Box 88)
      - "Black", Contemporary American Theater Festival, Shepherdstown, WV; Williamstown Theater Festival, Williamstown, MA; Women's Project and Productions, New York, NY (Box 88)
      - Black Water, 2 folders (Box 88)
      - "Black Water", opera (Box 89)
      - A Bloodsmoor Romance, 2 folders (Box 89)
      - By the North Gate (Box 89)
      - Childwold, 2 folders (Box 89)
      - Contemporary Short Fiction / edited by Joyce Carol Oates (Box 89)
      - Contraries: Essays (Box 89)
      - Crossing the Border, 2 folders (Box 89)
      - "Cry Me a River", Cambridge Theatre Company (Box 89)
      - Cybele (Box 89)
      - "Daisy", film adaptation (Box 89)
      - "Darling I'm Telling You", Raven Theater, Chicago; Risley Theatre, Cornell University (Box 89)
      - Do With Me What You Will (Box 89)
      - Double Delight (Box 89)
      - "The Eclipse", Ensemble Studio Theatre, New York, NY (Box 89)
      - The Edge of Impossibility (Box 89)
      - Expensive People (Box 89)
      - The Fabulous Beasts (Box 89)
      - First Love (Box 89)
      - First Person Singular: Writers on Their Craft (Box 89)
      - Foxfire, 2 folders (Box 89)
      - "Foxfire", film adaptation (Box 89)
      - A Garden of Earthly Delights (Box 89)
      - George Bellows: American Artist (Box 89)
      - The Goddess and Other Women (Box 89)
      - "Greensleeves", Drew University (Box 89)
      - "Gulf War", Burning House Group, Minneapolis; Ensemble Studio Theatre, New York, NY (Box 89)
      - Haunted: Tales of the Grotesque (Box 90)
      - "Heat", Penlight Theatre, Minneapolis (Box 90)
      - Heat and Other Stories (Box 90)
      - "Here She Is!", Philadelphia Theatre for New Plays (Box 90)
      - "How Do You Like Your Meat?", Long Wharf Theatre, New Haven, CT (Box 90)
      - The Hungry Ghosts (Box 90)
      - I Lock My Door Upon Myself (Box 90)
      - "I Stand Before You Naked" (Box 90)
        American Place Theater, New York, NY
        American Renegade Theatre, North Hollywood
        Attic Theatre Ensemble, Los Angeles
        French production: Robert Cordier
        Mount Holyoke College; Powertap Productions, Chicago
        The Schoolhouse, Croton Falls, NY
        Slightly Askew Players, Santa Barbara
        The Wooden-O, Los Angeles
      - "In Darkest America", Actors Theater of Louisville (Box 90)
      - "In the Region of Ice", film adaptation (Box 90)
      - Invisible Woman (Box 90)
      - Kindred Passions (Box 90)
      - Last Days (Box 90)
      - Lives of the Twins (Box 90)
      - Love and Its Derangements (Box 90)
      - Man Crazy (Box 90)
      - Marriages and Infidelities, 3 folders (Box 90)
      - Marya: a Life (Box 90)
      - "Miracle Play", New Phoenix Repertory Company, New York, NY (Box 90)
      - My Heart Laid Bare (Box 90)
      - Mysteries of Winterthurn (Box 90)
      - Nemesis (Box 90)
      - New Heaven, New Earth (Box 90)
      - Night-Side: Eighteen Tales (Box 90)
      - Night Walks (Box 90)
      - On Boxing, 2 folders (Box 91)
      - "Ontological Proof of My Existence", Cubiculo Theatre, New York, NY; Swedish production; Thunder Road Ensemble, Chicago; 24th Street Experiment, San Antonio; West-Mon Repertory, Houston (Box 91)
      - The Oxford Book of American Short Stories (Box 91)
      - "The Perfectionist", McCarter Theatre, Princeton, NJ (Box 91)
      - The Poisoned Kiss and Other Stories (Box 91)
      - Prize Stories: the O'Henry Awards, various years (Box 91)
      - "Procedure", Action Theatre, Louisville, KY; Actors Theatre of Louisville: 1992 (Box 91)
      - The Profane Art: Essays and Reviews (Box 91)
      - Raven's Wing (Box 91)
      - Reading the Fights (Box 91)
      - "The Rehearsal", Ensemble Studio Theatre, New York, NY (Box 91)
      - The Rise of Life on Earth (Box 91)
      - "The Sacrifice"/"The Key", Aldrich Museum of Contemporary Art, Ridgefield, CT (Box 91)
      - The Seduction and Other Stories (Box 91)
      - A Sentimental Education (Box 91)
      - "Smooth Talk", film adaptation (Box 91)
      - Snake Eyes (Box 91)
      - Solstice (Box 91)
      - Son of the Morning (Box 91)
      - The Sophisticated Cat (Box 91)
      - Soul/Mate (Box 91)
      - "Sunday Dinner", American Place Theatre, New York, NY (Box 91)
      - "The Sweet Enemy" (Box 91)
      - Tenderness (Box 91)
      - them (Box 91)
      - Three Plays (Box 91)
      - The Time Traveler (Box 91)
      - "Tone Clusters", Firehouse Theatre Project, Richmond, VA; Guthrie on First, Minneapolis; Manbites Dog Theatre Company, Duke University; SoHo Rep; Theatre du Rond-Point, Paris (Box 91)
      - The Triumph of the Spider Monkey (Box 92)
      - "The Triumph of the Spider Monkey", Classical Theatre Ensemble, Cubiculo Theater, New York, NY; Curtains Theatre, Houston; Los Angeles Theatre Center (Box 92)
      - "The Truth-Teller", Circle Repertory Company (Box 92)
      - Unholy Loves (Box 92)
      - Upon the Sweeping Flood (Box 92)
      - We Were the Mulvaneys (Box 92)
      - What I Lived For, 2 folders (Box 92)
      - The Wheel of Love and Other Stories, 2 folders (Box 92)
      - Where Are You Going, Where Have You Been? (Box 92)
      - Where Is Here? (Box 92)
      - Will You Always Love Me? (Box 92)
      - With Shuddering Fall (Box 92)
      - "The Woman Who Laughed", Playwrights Theatre of East Hampton; Sharon Stage, Sharon, CT (Box 92)
      - (Woman) Writer: Occasions and Opportunities (Box 92)
      - Women Whose Lives Are Food, Men Whose Lives Are Money (Box 92)
      - Wonderland (Box 92)
      - You Can't Catch Me (Box 92)
      - You Must Remember This, 2 folders (Box 92)
      - Zombie (Box 92)
  - Audiocassettes
    - "American Appetites (excerpts)/Glass" (Box 93)
    - "A Bloodsmoor Romance radio features NPR12/29/82 / Angel of Light AMF 1/83" (Box 93)
    - "Black Water Duffy / Oates 9/28/93" (Box 93)
    - "Black Water based on the novel by Joyce Carol Oates, music by Jeremy Beck, Russell Hall, University of Northern Iowa, March 29, 1995" (Box 93)
    - "Bookshelf 31.01.93 Joyce Carol Oates interviewed by Chris Bigsby" (Box 93)
    - "Bookworm recorded 8/16/93" KCRW, producer and host Michael Silverblatt (Box 93)
    - "Bookworm recorded 11/3/95" KCRW, producer and host Michael Silverblatt (Box 93)
    - "Centerlines WUGA-FM April 25, 1991 Joyce Carol Oates" (Box 93)
    - "Diane Rehm 11/19/96 Hour 2: Joyce Carol Oates We Were the Mulvaneys" (Box 93)
    - "For: Joyce Carol Oates Nedra's Song, Happy Opening Night! 10/1/93 Lucia Hwong" (Box 93)
    - "French interview Oct. 1992" (Box 93)
    - "Joyce and Jonathan [Schwartz] 9/1/96" (Box 93)
    - "Joyce Carol Oates, Ann Arbor, Michigan Mar. 29, 1978 / Joyce Carol Oates them prior to January, 1970; Anais Nin - date undetermined" (Box 93)
    - "Joyce Carol Oates, Emory Elliott USIS Bangkok 2[1?]/1/88" (Box 93)
    - "Joyce Carol Oates on 'The Green Room with Dorian' WFMU (E. Orange, NJ) 9/23/96" (Box 93)
    - "Joyce Carole [sic] Oates 'Thomas Mann's Dr. Faustus as a Portrait of an Artist'" (Box 93)
    - "Julianne Malveaux Show 10/19/94", 2 cassettes (Box 93)
    - "The Key Take One 1/10/91" (Box 93)
    - "L.A. Theatre Works: Black by Joyce Carol Oates" (Box 93)
    - "L.A. Theatre Works: Gulf War by Joyce Carol Oates" (Box 93)
    - "L.A. Theatre Works: The Perfectionist by Joyce Carol Oates", 2 cassettes (Box 93)
    - "L.A. Theatre Works: The Truth-Teller by Joyce Carol Oates" (Box 93)
    - "Larry King Show 5/14/90 JCO Washington, D.C." (Box 93)
    - "Meet the Playwright - Sharon Stage ("The Woman Who Laughed") 8/26/95 (aired 10/8/95)" / Randy Milroy's interview with Luci Arnaz (8/18/95) 'This W[ee]k in Litchfield Co.[nnecticut]'-'WWL' opening night 8/15/95" (Box 93)
    - "NPR feature Solstice 6/20/85" (Box 93)
    - "New Letters on the Air Joyce Carol Oates American Appetites 5/89" (Box 93)
    - "New York State Writers Institute, Humanities 355, the University at Albany, SUNY, Albany, NY 12222 Joyce Carol Oates 9/12/91 Book Show" (Box 93)
    - "Oates/Seton Hall Spring '86" (Box 93)
    - "PEN/Faulkner Award for Fiction Tenth Anniversary Celebration", 2 cassettes (Box 93)
    - "The Perfectionist Sept. 11th, '93", selections (Box 93)
    - Princeton University Alumni Day "2/91" (Box 93)
    - "Public radio book show #39: Joyce Carol Oates" (Box 93)
    - "Shopping read by Blair Brown, Symphony Space" (Box 93)
    - "Sunday Morning: On the Ropes January 23rd, ", 1994 (Box 93)
    - "Swedish Network Radio Aug. 5 & 6 1979" (Box 93)
    - "Tone Clusters Take Two 1/10/91" (Box 93)
    - "Two Gardens - Ed Cone" ("'The Stone Orchard/In Jana's Garden', songs composed by Ed Cone") (Box 93)
    - "Transformations of Play U[niversity] of Virginia 3/31/95" (Box 93)
    - "WAMC Book Show #339: Joyce Carol Oates" (Box 93)
    - "WNYC Joyce Carol Oates Summer Stage 9/13/90", "Central Park poetry & prose with Russell Banks" (Box 93)
    - "WNYC Leonard Lopate 20 Aug. 1996" (Box 93)
    - "Where Are You Going? Where Have You Been? / by Joyce Carol Oates. Read by Christine Baranski at 'Selected Shorts' Symphony Space, NYC", 2/25/87 (Box 93)
    - "Where Is Here? BBC Radio 3: Xmas '91" (Box 93)
    - "Will You Always Love Me?: a Selection" (Box 93)
    - "The Woman Who Laughed" (Box 93)
  - Audiotape
    - "Hendrick's Chapel 10/22/82" (Box 93)
  - Recorded books
    - American Appetites, c1990; New York: Caedmon (Box 94)
    - Because It Is Bitter, and Because It Is My Heart, undated; Studio City, Calif.: Dove Books on Tape, Inc. (Box 94)
    - Black Water, undated; Beverly Hills, Calif.: Dove Audio (Box 94)
    - "The Bloodstained Bridal Gown", See Memorabilia: Recorded books: The Mysteries of Winterthurn Part III
    - "The Devil's Half Acre", See Memorabilia: Recorded books: The Mysteries of Winterthurn Part II
    - Foxfire, c1994; St. Paul, Minn.: Penguin-Highbridge Audio (Box 94)
    - Murder for Love: Murder for Women - story collection includes Oates' "At the Paradise Motel, Sparks, Nevada", undated; Beverly Hills, CA: Dove Audio (Box 94)
    - The Mysteries of Winterthurn (in three parts), c1996; New York, NY: Recorded Books, Inc.
      - Part I: "The Virgin in the Rose Bower" (Box 94)
      - Part II: "The Devil's Half Acre" (Box 94)
      - Part III: "The Bloodstained Bridal Gown" (Box 94)
    - Night-Side (with Different Kinds of Dead by Ed Gorman), c1996; Grand Haven, Mich.: Brilliance Corp. (Box 94)
    - "The Virgin in the Rose Bower", See Memorabilia: Recorded books: The Mysteries of Winterthurn Part I
    - "The Yellow Wallpaper" / Charlotte Perkins Gilman, introd. by Joyce Carol Oates, undated; Princeton, NJ: The Spencer Library (Box 94)
    - Zombie, c1995; New York, N.Y.: Penguin Audiobooks (Box 94)
  - Videocassettes
    - "American Masters: Edgar Allan Poe" (Box 94)
    - "The Assignation [adapted from the story of Joyce Carol Oates]", c1995; PaNDa Films, Inc. (Box 94)
    - "Bookmark #214: Because It Is Bitter, and Because It Is My Heart 3.5.90" (Box 94)
    - "Centerstage IV: Underground", rough cut (Box 94)
    - "Charlie Rose 9/16/96" (Box 94)
    - "Electronic Dialogue - Joyce Carol Oates on Contemporary American Literature" (Box 94)
    - "Emory Elliott - Princeton: Black Water / Foxfire / What I Lived For" (Box 94)
    - "George Sand Conference Interlude and Tea with Joyce Carol Oates," (Hofstra University), November 16, 1996 (Box 94)
    - "Heat", reading of Joyce Carol Oates story; producer/director Elizabeth Anderman (Box 94)
    - "I Stand Before You Naked Mount Holyoke College", 12/27/96 (Box 94)
    - "In the Region of Ice" (Box 94)
    - "Joyce Carol Oates NTSC" (Box 94)
    - "Lies (sic) of the Twins (1991)" (Box 94)
    - "Milwaukee interview Summer '78" (Box 94)
    - "A Moveable Feast: Profiles of Contemporary American Authors Joyce Carol Oates American Appetites", c1990; In Our Time Arts Media, Inc.; 2 copies (Box 94)
    - "Nightwatch: Joyce Carol Oates" (Box 94)
    - "Norman the Killer" (Box 94)
    - "The Originals: Joyce Carol Oates 1989" (Box 94)
    - "Part 1: Poetry by E. Dickinson / Part 2: Poetry by J.C. Oates" (Box 94)
    - "Readers Theater JCO taped 3/19/88" (Box 94)
    - Ring [magazine] Anniversary 1997/July 1988 horse race at Meadowlands, NJ, pacer filly owned by Oates (Box 94)
    - "Sci-Fi Buzz #154: Women Horror Writers" (The Sci-Fi Channel), c1996 (Box 94)
    - "State of the Arts 1307: Oates/Musica Antiqua/Artes Magnus 12/05/94" (Box 94)
    - "Today [Show] 4/29/92 Black Water" (Box 94)
    - "A Word on Words: Oates What I Lived For WDCN/Nashville" (Box 94)
    - "Writers Forum: Joyce Oates 10-30-80" (Box 94)
- Book translations (Box 94)
  - Author's copies (Box 1P)
  - Translations
    - Czech, Danish, Dutch, Finnish (Box 2P)
    - Finnish, French (Box 3P)
    - French, German (Box 4P)
    - German, Greek, Hebrew, Hungarian, Italian (Box 5P)
    - Italian, Japanese, Korean, Lithuanian, Norwegian, Polish, Portuguese, Romanian, Russian, Slovenian, Spanish (Box 6P)
    - Spanish, Swedish, Turkish (Box 6AP)